Contact

9886354959 (Mobile) sunjsg@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/ in/sundara-moorthyparamanantham-04901548 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Python Statistics Requirements Analysis

Honors-Awards
Wall of Fame
Hackathon winner
Star of the quarter

Sundara Moorthy Paramanantham

Principal Data Scientist at Societe Generale Global Solution Centre Bangalore Urban

Summary

Driven by passion for creating value in an environment of shared ideas, efforts and responsibilities. Accomplished professional with nearly 16 years of experience spanning across diversified set of web technologies, n-tier systems, client server applications, process automation, transformation, reporting and 4 years in Machine learning, Artificial intelligence and data analytic's. Delivers efficient and reliable IT solutions and excels in building/leading teams in high-pressure environments. Committed to professionalism, highly organized, able to see the big picture while paying attention to small details, and exhibits excellent communication skills.

Experience

Societe Generale Global Solution Centre 14 years 4 months

Principal Data Scientist
October 2018 - Present (2 years 7 months)
Bangalore

- Lead data science enterprise practices;
- Engaging stakeholders and managing multiple projects;
- Setting up the data science and advanced analytics strategies and road map;
- Building and delivering data science and analytical projects into production;
- Developing framework for data and machine learning to be utilized effectively across enterprise;
- Implementing new AI and machine learning techniques on big data platform;
- Developing data science service catalogue and promoting data science to business:
- Coaching team of data scientists and analysts to provide business value proactively;
- Uplifting technical skills for the data science community across enterprise.

Assistant Vice President

April 2017 - September 2018 (1 year 6 months)

Bengaluru Area, India

- Lead data science enterprise practices;
- Engaging stakeholders and managing multiple projects;
- Setting up the data science and advanced analytics strategies and road map;
- Building and delivering data science and analytical projects into production;
- Developing framework for data and machine learning to be utilized effectively across enterprise;
- Implementing new AI and machine learning techniques on big data platform;
- Developing data science service catalogue and promoting data science to business;
- Coaching team of data scientists and analysts to provide business value proactively;
- Uplifting technical skills for the data science community across enterprise.

Project Manager

April 2013 - March 2017 (4 years)

Bengaluru Area, India

Senior Technical Lead

April 2011 - March 2013 (2 years)

Bengaluru Area, India

Technical Lead

April 2009 - March 2011 (2 years)

Bengaluru Area, India

Senior Software Engineer

January 2007 - March 2009 (2 years 3 months)

Bengaluru Area, India

Société Générale

Business Analyst

August 2007 - March 2008 (8 months)

Singapore

Worked with Societe Generale private banking, on order management, Relation ship management and FX option Pricers systems.

Cybernet Software System Inc

Programmer Analyst

March 2006 - December 2006 (10 months)

Chennai Area, India

Worked as a consultant in Societe Generale Global solution center, Bangalore

Prodapt
Software Programmer
October 2005 - March 2006 (6 months)

Chennai Area, India

Calsoft
Software Engineer
May 2004 - October 2005 (1 year 6 months)
Chennai Area, India

Education

International School of Engineering (INSOFE)

Postgraduate Program in Big Data Analytics and Optimization, Data Science,

Machine Learning and Optimization

Bharathidasan University

Master of Computer Applications - MCA, Computer Science

Bharathidasan University
Bachelor's degree, Industrial Electronics